Guide to the Charles H. Irby Papers, 1962-1975
Department of Special Collections
Charles H. Irby Papers,
1962-1975
Special Collections M0671
Irby, Charles H.
4.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Charles Irby, 1994.
Scope and Content
Primarily correspondence, memos, working notes and technical reports from work on ARPANET, Control Meta Language, Modular Programming System and software and interface applications while Irby was at SRI International and Xerox Park.
Access Terms
Cotton, Ira.; Deutsch, L. Peter.; Dornbush, Charles F.; Engelbart, Douglas C.; Kelley, Karl Cornell.; Lampson, Butler W.; Liddle, Dave.; Meyer, Ed.; Michener, Jim.; Mitchell, James G.; Paxton, William Hamilton.; Victor, Kenneth E.; Watson, Richard W.; White, James E.; Augmentation Research Center.; Bolt, Beranek and Newman, inc.; National Software Works.; Network Working Group.; SRI International.; Stanford Research Institute. Augmentation Research Center.; United States. Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency Software and Intelligent Systems Technology Office.; University of Southern California. Information Sciences Institute.; Control Meta Language.; Distributed Programming System.; Information storage and retrieval systems.; Modular Programming System.; Operating System Module.; Science--History.; Software engineering.; User interfaces (Computer systems)
Container List
- Invitation to organizational meeting about Management System Technology (MST) from J. Perry and C. Fields. Jan. 21, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CHI. "Display techniques for interactive text manipulation." National Computer Comference, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CHI et. al. "A Command meta language for NLS." June 28, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- JOHNSON, Paul R. and THOMAS, Robert H. BBN-TENEX. "The Maintenance of Duplicate Databases." Network Working Group, RFC #677, NIC #31507. Jan. 27, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- DCE. "Coordinated information services for a discipline of mission-oriented community." Presented at Second Annual Computer Communications Conference in San Jose, CA., Jan. 24, 1973. ARC Journal Accession No.: 12445, ARC Publication Time: Dec. 12, 1972. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ANDREWS, Donald I. "Line processor - a device for amplification of display terminal capabilities for text manipulation." National Computer Conference, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ANDERSON, Bob. "Informal position paper on office animation." Jan. 25, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- OESTREICHER, HEAFNER, and ROTHENBERG. "CONNECT, a user-oriented communications service." IA Document 35, Version 5. Jan. 1974. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- PERRY, John S. "Thoughts on the automated office." Dec. 7, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- VEZZA and HAVERTY. "Informal position paper on management system technology." n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abstract, paper, and fomulas about impact of emerging augmentation technology and ARC. Nov. 14, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Reaction to JLP/CF wish list." Jan. 25, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Reaction to JPL/CF wish list and ARC/NLS status with respect to it." Jan. 27, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- RWW. "Some higher level issues for the MST meeting." Jan. 28, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- DCE, RWW, and NORTON. "The Augment knowledge workshop." Paper presented at the National Computer Conference, New York City, June 1973.ARC Journal Accession No.: 14724, ARC Publication Time: March 1, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- BRESSLER and THOMAS. "Inter-entity communication - an experiment." Network Working Group, RFC #441, NIC #13773, Distribution to include subgroup NDIG. Jan. 19, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ELLIOT, POTAS, and VANDAM. Unpublished appendix to "Computer-assisted tracing of text evolution." FJCC, 1971. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ELLIOT, POTAS, and VANDAM. "Computer assisted tracing of text evolution." AFIPS Proceedings, Fall Joint Computer Conference, 1971, vol. 39, p. 533-540. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- RWW. "Some factors which a network graphics protocol must consider." Network Working Group, RFC #192, NIC #7137, July 12, 1971. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Computer program sent to USC-ISIC, Oct. 14, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Computer program. July 21, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- RWW. "Continuation of national software works developments." Proposal for research SRI No. ISU 75-94. Prepared for Information Processing Techniques Office, Advanced Research Projects Agency, Arlington, VA. June, 10, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "1st rough draft of the Programmers' guide to writing language modules for the debugger." Sept. 2, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- E-mail re. NSW debugger. June 19, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- E-mail release of Journal document #25056; documentation added to Control Meta Language (CML) to accomodate NSW needs. Apr. 11, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, Arlington, VA. "Standard DoD high order language." Memorandum for IPTO Principal investigations. Rec'd May 30, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Extensions to the L10 programming language for the DEC PDP-10 and DEC PDP-11." (Box 1, Folder 6)
- SCHANTZ, Richard. BBN-TENEX. "Commentary on procedure calling as a network protocol." Network Working Group, RFC #684, NIC #32252, Apr. 15, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- MEYER, N. Dean. "Executive information tools." Draft. Sept. 11, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CHI. "Command Meta Language -- CML." Oct. 25, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ABBOTT, Russell J. "Command language processor for flexible interface design." Information Automation Project, USC-ISI. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Workshop on machine independent graphics." Program from ACM-SIGGRAPH/NBS, held at the National Bureau of Standards, Gaithersburg, MD, Apr. 22-23, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Black 3-ring binder (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB, Nov. 4, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB, Nov. 4, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB, Oct. 21, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. OSI. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. CML. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. FEDATA, Writable data. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. NSWEXEC-CML. Grammars. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. NLSGRAM. Grammars. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. NLS-PARSEFUNCTIONS. Grammars. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. L1011STGMGT. L10 Runtime. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. GRAMLDR. L10 Runtime. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. XL10RUNTIME. L10 Runtime. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- Computer program by CHI for USC-ISIB. XL10DATA. L10 Runtime. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 1)
- TNLS-8 Quick reference card. SRI-ARC 1-SEP-74-23753. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "ARPANET Directory, July 1975." NIC 32992. Prepared by NIC for ARPA, Information Processing Techniques Office. Contract No. F30602-75-C-0123. Report. Feb. 20, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- KRUTAR, R. "Conversational systems programming." Xerox-PARC memo. rec'd by CHI. May 15, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- "Modular programming." n.d., 2 copies. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- WHP. "What are we looking for from MPS?" June 10, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- JGM. "MPSDATA" Xerox-PARC. Jan. 25, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- LPD. "Full tilt into the heffalump trap." Apr. 11, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- JGM. "Contribution to research report to management." Report to Dave Allison. Apr. 21, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- WHP. "MPL Datatype facility." May 18, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- McCREIGHT, Ed. ""MPL Meeting notes, re. MPL debugger." June 6, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- WHP. "What are we looking for from MPS?" June 10, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- RWW. "development notes." Rec'd by CHI Dec. 26, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- RWW. "mpl" Rec'd by CHI Dec. 13, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Suggested NLS MPS Organization." Flow chart. n.d., (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CFD. "One view of modular programming and MPS." (Box 2, Folder 4)
- WHP. "What are we looking for from MPS?" June 10, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Conversion." Draft of paper about conversion of NLS to run in MPS environment. Feb. 15, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CHI. "Conversion." Draft of paper about conversion of NLS to run in MPS environment. Feb. 15, 1973., marked copy. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- LPD. "Control." Memo rec'd by CHI May 18, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- BWL. "Modular Programming System." n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- LPD. Paper about conversion of NLS to run in MPS environment. Feb. 26, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- LPD. "Software engineering crisis." Feb. 20, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- JGM. "Model for MPS processes and environments, MPS 4.0." Xerox-PARC/SRI. May 16, 1972., (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- JGM. "Introduction to the Modular Programming System, MPS 2.0." Xerox-PARC/SRI. May 12, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CHI. "Command meta language system." SRI. Augment, 27266, 1976. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ANDREWS, Donald I. "Line processor - a device for amplification of display terminal capabilities for text manipulation." SRI. National Computer Conference, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Telnet protocol specification." NIC #18639. August, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- DAVIDSON, John. "An Echoing strategy for satellite links." Network Working Group, RFC #357, NIC #10599, June 26, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- DAVIDSON. "Comments on the RCTE TELNET Option." NWG/RFC #563, NIC #18775, Aug. 28, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CROCKER, D. and Postal, J. "Remote controlled transmission & echoing TELNET option." Network Working Group, NWG/RFC #560, NIC #18492, Aug. 20, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- RWW. Xerox. "Emerging technical applications in information retrieval." National Science Foundation on Scientific and Technical Information, Washington, DC, Oct. 1973. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Towards the design of an online calendar subsystem." rough draft distributed by MJOURNAL. May 20, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- LYNCH. "TENEX system tuning parameters." Mar. 8, 1975. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CLEMENTS, R. BBN. "TENEX extensions for paged files." NWG/RFC #683, NIC #32251, Apr. 3, 1975. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- JEW. "Modules and their procedure calls." Oct. 16, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Collection of papers representing the design documents for the distributed TENEX system on the ARPANET. Nov. 8, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- EARLEY, Jay and CAIZERGUES, Paul. "Method for incrementally compiling languages with nested statement structure." In Communications of the ACM, vol. 15, no. 12, Dec. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- PARNAS, D.L. "On the criteria to be used in decomposing systems into modules." In Communications of the ACM, vol. 15, no. 12, Dec. 1972. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- CFD. "Sample use of uniform referent capabilities in MPS." May 18, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- CFD. "Evaluation and automatic deferencing." May 24, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- GOLDBERG, NEUMANN, and WENSLEY. SRI, Computer Science Group. "Survey of fault-tolerant computing systems (revised)." Aug. 8, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- NEUMANN. SRI. "Hierarchical framework for fault-tolerant computing systems." IEEE Computer Society Conference, San Francisco, Sept. 1972. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- EHS, DDC. "MPS debugger." Jan. 3, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- RUBIN, S. "Computable command programming." Dec. 30, 1968. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- YOUNGS, Eric A. "Error-proneness in programming." Section of author's UNC psychology thesis. 1969. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- CFD. "Overview of the Basic File System." Jan. 11, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- McCARTHY, John. SU-AI. "Arbitrary character sets." NWG/RFC #373, NIC #11058. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "A Graphics protocol for text handling." Apr. 25, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- DUVALL, W.S. "New character generator editor." Mar. 1, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- BRUNON, Joseph. "Group dynamics and visual thinking." (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Structure of local and global strings." Sept. 22, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- DOCMPS. July 18, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- FERRARI, Domenico. "Improving locality by critical working sets." In Communications of the ACM, vol. 17, no. 11 Dec. 1974. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- BWL, JGM, and Satterwhite. Xerox PARC. "On the transfer of control between contexts." n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "MPS debugger." first draft. n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- BWL. Xerox-PARC. "New control transfer mechanism." Apr. 10, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "CML code", Red 3-ring binder (Box 3)
- Computer program. L1011, OSI-CLI. Oct. 24, 1975. (Box 3)
- New CLI divider (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES. Oct. 21, 1975. (Box 3)
- OSI divider (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCE, XOSI-CLI. Oct. 20, 1975. (Box 3)
- Computer program. L1011, OSI-CLI. Oct. 20, 1975. (Box 3)
- DATA divider (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES, XFEDATA. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 3)
- Compactor divider (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES, CGRAMLDR. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES, CGRAM. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 3)
- Parse functions divider (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES, XFEROUTINES. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 3)
- Computer program. NSW-SOURCES, XNLS-PARSEFUNTIONS. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 3)
- RWW. "National software works developments." Proposal for research SRI No. ISU 74-132. SIR-ARC 23352. Prepared for Information Processing Techniques Office, ARPA. July 1, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CFD. "Comments on proposed coding standards." Apr. 17, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "NLS file structure." June 6, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Xerox meeting notes." Notes from meeting held at Xerox-PARC on Feb. 15, 1972. Rec'd Feb. 22, 1972. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Yet another look at the MPS conversion." Mar. 29, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- RWW. "Notes to show scope of a software engineering workshop." July 4, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- WENNERSTROM, Bruce. "Now it's pedal power to fight pollution." In Mechanix Illustrated, Feb. 1973. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Draft design for a text/graphics proposal." July 13, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- MICHENER, COTTON, KELLEY, LIDDLE, MEYER. "Graphics protocol." Network Working Group, RFC #493, NIC #15358, Apr. 26, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- THOMAS, Elaine. BBN. "Proposed network graphics protocol." Jan. 11, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Notes on Thomas' "Proposed network graphics protocol." (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "Summary of Display Primitives as of 1 Apr 72 (not a complete set)." DPRIM. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "Graphics protocol for text handling." July 1, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- DCE. SRI. "Augmenting human intellect: a conceptual framework." AFOSR-3223. Prepared for Director of Information Sciences Air Force Office of Scientific Research. Contract AF 49(638)-1024. Oct. 1962. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- HAY and RULIFSON. SRI. "MOL940: Preliminary specification for an algol-like machine-oriented language for the SDS 940." Interim technical report 2. Prepared for NASA, Langley Research Center. Contract NAS1-5904. March, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- DCE. SRI. "Human intellect augmentation techniques." Final report. Prepared for NASA, Langley Research Center. Contract NAS1-5904. July, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- BELLEVILLE, Robert Louis. "Portfolio." n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- DCE and ARC staff. SRI. "Computer-augmented management-system research and development of augmentation facility." ARPA Order No. 0967. April 1970. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Resource Sharing, the ARPANET's goal." First draft. Sept. 25, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Resource Sharing, the ARPANET's goal." Second draft. Oct. 24, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Computer program. Oct. 16, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Computer program. Oct. 20, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- RETZ, David L. "Overview of the ELF operating system." n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Computer program. June 2, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Computer program. Nov. 6, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Summary of thoughts on the HELP system." Oct. 29, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- EKM. "Description of Form System proposal." May 24, 1974. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Meeting notes. Sept. 25, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "National Software Works Developments." Quarterly report. Sept. 16, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Computer program: procedures to perform externally callable display functions in the NSW frontend, definition of display data structure. Sept. 18, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Computer program. PCPB8 - Data structure encoding." Sept. 8, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Notes on PCPB8 data structures... Sept. 17, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "New CML features for NSW." Journal doc. # 25056. Jan. 10, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Operating System Module (OSM). Journal doc. #26458. Sept. 16, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Frontend status as of 9-Jun-75." June 9, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- RWW. "Standard NSW frontend control functions." Journal doc. #25495. May 9, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Rome Air Development Center, Grifiss Air Force Base, New York. "Statement of work for NSW frontend, protocols and tools. PR B-5-3324." June 12, 1975.Massachusetts Computer Associates, Inc. "National Software Works: Technical proposal, Proposal Number P - 7014." Apr. 30, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- DPS Processes. Journal doc. # 26282. Sept. 8, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Description of internal structure of DPS process on Tenex. Journal doc. #26170. July 23, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Conventions used by CLI when interacting via MSG. Sept. 8, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Network UNIX." NWG/RFC #681, NIC #32157, May 14, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- RWW. "Estimate of PDP 11 Core Usage and issues it raises." July 8, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Breakdown of the address space used by the CLI on the PDP-10. Journal doc. #26144. Aug. 5, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Discussion about HOST name recognition. Journal doc. #32806. June 30, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Discussion about annotation. Journal doc. #32840. June 30, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Description of use of NSW. June 30, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Notes about running standalone L10 programs. Apr. 17, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Computer program. Nov. 3, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Computer program. Oct. 20, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- DCE. "Summary list of unique developments and contributions by ARC." Oct. 9, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- RIDDLE, Liz. AFDSC. "Comparative study of editing and runoff systems." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- "ICC Special Project on Networking." Conference program. Oct. 1972. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- RITHCIE and THOMPSON. Bell Labs. "UNIX time-sharing system." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- USC/ISI. "Video Display requirements." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- WHP. "MPS segmentation system overview." Feb. 4, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- BALTZER, Robert. "Software production facility." Re. phone discussion with DCE. June 1973. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Notes on transfer of control between MPS modules. July 18, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Network Graphics Group. "Proposed network graphics protocol." Aug. 28, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- BWL. "MPS." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Network Graphics Group. "Proposed network graphics protocol." ARPA NIC, SRI. NIC #19933. Note #5. Oct. 10, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Computer program. "MPS Free Storage Package." Mar. 27, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- "Towards the design of an information management system." Journal doc. #17394. June, 21,1973. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- JEW. Journal doc. July, 30,1973. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- POPEK and KLINE. UCLA Computer Science Dept. "Veritable Secure Operating System Software." Published in AFIPS conference proceedings, Vol. 43, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- LPD. "WYLBUR and TENEX from another viewpoint." Journal doc. #9919. Apr. 20, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- VALLEE, Jacques. "Preliminary proposal for NLS directory editor." Apr. 20, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- "Proposed NLS code format and documentation standards." Apr. 13, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- WHP. Evolving design to allow command backup in NLS. Feb. 22, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Computer program. Nov. 12, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- DCE. Notes on back-delete operations. Aug. 28, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- ALLEN, ASHCROFT, and FLORENTIN. "Inferences from formal language definitions." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- BURGE. IBM. "Functions for Parsing." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- LEE. "Vienna definition language: a generalization of instruction definitions." Prepared for the SIGPLAN Symposium on Programming Language Definition." Apr. 1969. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- WEGNER. "Notes for a lecture on 'Theories of Semantics." Symposium on Programming Languages Definition, San Francisco, August, 1969. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- BEALS, LaFRANCE, NORTHCOTE. "Automatic generation of Floyd Production Production Syntactic Analyzers." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- SCHNEIDER. "Some syntactic methods for specifying extendible programming languages." (Box 5, Folder 7)
- McGOWEN. "On the euivalence of mechanical evaluation strategies." n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- PRATT. "Semantic modeling by hierarchical graphs." July 1969. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- NIEVERGELT and IRLAND. "NUCLEOL as a formal system." (Box 5, Folder 8)
- WHITNEY and MOOERS. "Formal definition of the scan algorith of the TRAC T-64 language." July 1969. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- "Interdata Model 7/32 Processor." Product Bulletin. 1974. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- PINE and SCHWEPPE. "Fortran language anticipation and prompting system." Reprinted with permission from the Proceedings ACM73 Annual Conference. August 1973. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- "MPS free storage package." Jan. 2, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "A Look at the MPS conversion." Revised edition of paper 14928. Mar. 22, 1973. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- JGM. Xerox-PARC/SRI. "MPS Language reference manual. MPS 11.0." Sept. 4, 1972. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- JGM and Satterthwaite. Xerox-PARC/SRI. "Debugger meetings and specifications." Sept. 4, 1972. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- "MPS segmentation machinery." n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- MPS debugger documentation. Feb. 25, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Suggestion for organization of NLS software people. Dec. 29, 1971. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- MADER. "Network debugging protocol." RFC #643. July 1974. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- CML documentation. Nov. 21, 1973. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- "Modular Programming Language (MPL)." n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Computer program: procedures to perform externally callable display functions in the NSW frontend, definition of display data structure. Sept. 18, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- DCE. SRI-ARC. "Design considerations for knowledge workshop terminals." ARC journal #14851. Paper submitted for National Computer Conference, NY, June 1973. Mar. 14, 1973. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- DCE. "Coordinated information services for a discipline or mission-oriented community." Computer Communications Conference, Jan. 24, 1973. Dec. 12,1972. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- RAPHAEL. SRI. "Symbol manipulation by digital computer." Prepared for Encyclopedia of Linguistics, Information, and Control. Apr.1966. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- RAPHAEL. SRI. "Aspects and applications of symbol manipulation." Proceedings. A.C.M National Meeting, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- SRI-ARC. "NLS-8 Glossary. July 16, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- WHITE. SRI-ARC. "Procedure call protocol, version two." Nov. 22, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- SRI-ARC. "Output processor user's guide." ARC 32812. July 28, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- SRI-ARC. "Format library." SRI ARC 25764. Mar. 6, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- POSTEL. SRI-ARC. "National Software Works Protocols, version 2." Jan. 1, 1975. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Window user interface documentation. Jan. 28, 1976. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- RWW. "Comments on strategies to support an integrated SPF." July 25, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- DCE. Note of interest in collaboration. June 21, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 1)